<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Some thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-06T11:42:08+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://burningTyger.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[burningTyger]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ubuntu and the MacBook Pro 3.1]]></title>
    <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/02/06/ubuntu-and-the-macbook-pro-3-dot-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-06T11:29:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/02/06/ubuntu-and-the-macbook-pro-3-dot-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Running Linux on a 2007 MacBook Pro aka 3.1 is quite a nice experience. Not just
because it breathes fresh air into an "older" Mac but also because it runs a lot
smoother under Linux than Mac OS X. Well, later versions of Mac OS X like Mavericks.</p>

<p>I know, the machine is not quite state of the art but if Apple decides to let users
install 10.9 on their machines they should at least make sure it's a smooth experience.</p>

<p>But it's not. I have 4GB of memory in my MBP and it's still slow and sluggish at
best. Not very nice. And looking at the specs the MBP is not bad.</p>

<p>Anyway, putting Ubuntu on it was ok but here and there there are some issues that
need some tinkering. One of them was the graphics card. It works but there are always
error messages in Gnome after startup. I tried the Nouveau driver but it didn't
really work. Issues here and there. So I tried the Nvidia driver which worked better
but still produced the error messages. I think it was the 319 driver.</p>

<p>Yesterday after looking into that again I tried the newer updated 319 driver and
voila, no more error messages.</p>

<p>So if you come here looking for the MacBook Pro late 2007 3.1 model with a G84M
video card, also known as Nvidia GeForce 8600M GT do not look further but use the
NVIDIA binary Xorg driver called <code>nvidia-319-updates</code>. It works well. It's proprietary
but that's the price for a working video card.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to fix a corrupt Mac OS X hard drive (catolog)]]></title>
    <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/01/05/how-to-fix-a-corrupt-mac-os-x-hard-drive-catolog/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T11:19:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/01/05/how-to-fix-a-corrupt-mac-os-x-hard-drive-catolog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Usually you won't notice a corrupt hard drive under Mac OS X unless it
tells you so or because you checked your hard drive in Disk Utils.</p>

<p>If it is broken to some degree Disk Utils will let you fix them or tells
you to reformat your hard drive. In some cases that is not an option.</p>

<p>In my case I had a broken hard drive that wouldn't let me resize the
partitions and I wasn't able to install Linux on a separate partition.
Everything failed. My DuperDrive only reads CDs. So no OS X install DVD
to run DiskUtils from another drive. Runing the Disk Utils from the
recovery partition didn't let me fix or reformat the hard drive either
(because it's on the same hard drive after all) and the internet
recovery mode didn't even start. Neither the USB recovery disk I
created.</p>

<p>Being smart I burned on another Mac a rare CD-sized Lubuntu Distro which
I also intended to install on my main Mac. It offers gparted, the Linux
partition manager. Running that from another medium brought hope to
fixing the hard drive partition mess. It failed. It said something about
a corrupt catalog on the mac partition and wasn't able to fix it. Not
being able to fix the problem in one place also meant no resizing the
partition in the other place. And I was stuck with the same old disk.</p>

<p>Turning out to be even smarter than that I remembered single mode for my
Mac. I rebooted the Mac and started up in single mode. Now this has two
advantages: first it is the system loaded in memory and second it has
all the mac specific tools on board (unlike gparted with Linux tools).
Running fsck on the mac partition worked its way through broken b-trees
and corrupt catalog data and in the end I had a working hard drive with
no more errors and I was able to resize the partition to create free
space on it which Lubuntu magically filled with Linux.</p>

<p>I don't exacly remember the fsck comman I used but it was something
simple. Like, fix that partition when you find errors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
