<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Some thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-03T21:17:35+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://burningTyger.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[burningTyger]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to fix a corrupt Mac OS X hard drive (catolog)]]></title>
    <link href="http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/01/05/how-to-fix-a-corrupt-mac-os-x-hard-drive-catolog/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-05T11:19:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://burningTyger.github.com/blog/2014/01/05/how-to-fix-a-corrupt-mac-os-x-hard-drive-catolog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Usually you won't notice a corrupt hard drive under Mac OS X unless it
tells you so or because you checked your hard drive in Disk Utils.</p>

<p>If it is broken to some degree Disk Utils will let you fix them or tells
you to reformat your hard drive. In some cases that is not an option.</p>

<p>In my case I had a broken hard drive that wouldn't let me resize the
partitions and I wasn't able to install Linux on a separate partition.
Everything failed. My DuperDrive only reads CDs. So no OS X install DVD
to run DiskUtils from another drive. Runing the Disk Utils from the
recovery partition didn't let me fix or reformat the hard drive either
(because it's on the same hard drive after all) and the internet
recovery mode didn't even start. Neither the USB recovery disk I
created.</p>

<p>Being smart I burned on another Mac a rare CD-sized Lubuntu Distro which
I also intended to install on my main Mac. It offers gparted, the Linux
partition manager. Running that from another medium brought hope to
fixing the hard drive partition mess. It failed. It said something about
a corrupt catalog on the mac partition and wasn't able to fix it. Not
being able to fix the problem in one place also meant no resizing the
partition in the other place. And I was stuck with the same old disk.</p>

<p>Turning out to be even smarter than that I remembered single mode for my
Mac. I rebooted the Mac and started up in single mode. Now this has two
advantages: first it is the system loaded in memory and second it has
all the mac specific tools on board (unlike gparted with Linux tools).
Running fsck on the mac partition worked its way through broken b-trees
and corrupt catalog data and in the end I had a working hard drive with
no more errors and I was able to resize the partition to create free
space on it which Lubuntu magically filled with Linux.</p>

<p>I don't exacly remember the fsck comman I used but it was something
simple. Like, fix that partition when you find errors.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
